https://github.com/probinso

### Personal Statement

I have 7+ years experience, solving increasingly difficult problems with software. My projects span products and research including data pipelines/management, medical informatics, programming languages, computer securities, audio, image, and text processing. I have developed strong interests in scientific computing, information retrieval, machine learning, and education. I look forward to building stable solutions with you.

### Persistant Experience :

Python C, C++ Linux TDD

R, dplyr ETpX Git Ticketing Systems

# Work Experience \_

Thinkful (Part Time) - Data Science Techichal Expert Jan. 2019 - present
Advised career transitioners in mastery of professional and data science topics
Provided safe environment for 1:1 training and instruction in a remote-first setting

NASA Jet Propulsion Lab - Graduate Data Science Intern June 2018 - Sept. 2018

Designed & developed Expert Modeling/Recommender System, by extending the Author-Topic-Model Prototyped matching experts against mission critical anomalies, automating expensive tasks Implemented stable/principled text normalization, tokenization, and model evaluation Open Source contributions to the gensim's natural language processing library

Technologies: Python, nltk, gensim, pyLDAvis, pandas, jupyter

OHSU Fair Neuroimaging Lab - Research Assistant

Contributed to workflows and analytics tools for studying Microbiome populations Supported research on developing brains, including ABCD, and several ADHD/ASD studies Developed processing pipeline and audit tools for reported data and FMRI images

Technologies: Python, Bash, R, neo4j, ponyorm, stan, GitLab

### Contractor/Consultant

## RGB Optics / C&W Energy USA (Part Time)

Nov. 2015 - Aug. 2018

Oct. 2017 - June 2018

Developed custom photo image processing tools for low cost spectral profile analysis Authored educational material in light pollution's effect on economy, biology, and technology Developed a cloud memoizing data pipeline for caching computationally expensive operations Provided live technology tutorials and consulting on optimization and image processing

ComScore June 2016 - Sept. 2016

Worked to support large, custom, memory mapped, data store for demographic analysis PDXCodeGuild (Part Time)

June 2016

Developed and taught introductory python course material for coding boot-camp

Melinae March 2016

Setup infrastructure in AWS to enable secure & sustainable remote-first workflow Provided hands on training in Python and R to industry professionals

Technologies: Python, numpy, skimage, R, AWS, PostgreSQL, Perl, C++, Jira, ZenHub

Galois Inc. - Research Engineer April 2014 - Dec 2015

Contributed to PPAML, Overseas Voting Foundation, Safeware

Developed processing pipelines and workflows to enable evaluator work for DARPA programs Produced biannual quantitative and qualitative reports on for DARPA and language developers Participated in programs sharing new technologies to research and industry professionals

Technologies: Python, SLURM, Scala, Figaro, Chimpy, Docker, Jira, Basecamp

EMC<sup>2</sup> Isilon Storage - Software Development Engineer Dec. 2012 - July 2013

Brought to schedule a lagging anchor release feature in approximately 5 months Designed and developed password manager to support Data At Rest Encryption Wrote unit tests using libcheck to attain > 80% code coverage

Technologies: C, C++, Python, SQLite, Subversion, FreeBSD, OpenSSL

# Neato Projects

Topic modeling and applications, a presentation for non-statisticians PATEX Ocean/bioacoustic anomaly localization and analysis ACOio, tensorflow, scipy, Python Workshop collaborative introduction to GitHub and slides markdown, bash, github.api Morphological Watershedding Algorithms pyspark, numpy, ndimage, Python Relevance Vector Machine Julia Information Retrieval Cluster/Rank Demo Harness flask, numpy, nltk, sklearn, Python Gene Data Breast Cancer Drug Predictor R, caret Distributed Fully Homomorphic Encryption System Hadoop, Sagemath Concurrent Elliptic Curve Cryptography Module Sagemath, Erlang Multilingual Analysis of Subordinating and Coordinating Conjunctions R, Perl AdaRailz Concurrent Model Train Control System Ada

## Education

## Oregon Health Science University

CSLU

Computer Science MSc 2016 - present

Expected End: Sept. 2019

#### Courses :

\* Advanced Topics in Machine Learning
Deep Learning
Machine Learning
Artificial Intelligence
Statistical Methods
Univariate Statistical Analysis
Analysis of Sequences

- \* Natural Language Processing

  \* Advanced Topics in Signal P
- \* Advanced Topics in Signal Processing Speech Signal Processing Problem Solving with Large Clusters Image Processing Information Retrieval Computing Ethics

## Western Washington University

Computer Science BS, Mathematics Minor Sept. 2007 - June 2012

#### Electives :

Homomorphic Encryption Systems Cryptography & Elliptic Curves Artificial Intelligence Natural Language Processing Functional Programming Computer Science

Computer Graphics Number Theory Elementary Real Analysis Abstract Algebra Linear Algebra I/II